放下来  把他弄下来
Bajar lo. Get him down.
你跟小妞们有什么仇啊
What you got against chickens?
因为你昨晚有个姑娘被噎到了
One got choked last night, thanks to you.
33岁男性  咳血  高烧
33-year-old male with hemoptysis, fever...
我们能谈谈吗
Can't we even talk about it?
你不道歉  就没得谈
You can't apologize, we can't talk.
他还有刺伤
And puncture wounds.
我不会为正确的举动向你道歉
I'm not apologizing for doing the right thing.
对我撒谎可不是什么正确的事
Lying to me was not the right thing.
刺伤是钉在十字架上造成的
Puncture wounds are from a crucifixion.
我说谎是为了救病人的命
I lied to save my patient's life.
我没骗你  我骗的是我的上司
I didn't lie to you. I lied to my boss.
这些解释够吗
Either of those arguments working yet?
看来我不用参加周六的婚礼了
I guess that means I don't have to go to the wedding on Saturday.
你是说医院董事长的婚礼吗
The hospital's chairman of the board?
我不会放他鸽子  你也不会
I'm not gonna stand him up, and neither are you.
我讨厌死婚礼了
I loathe weddings
还有人们的各种伪善面目
and their seven levels of hypocrisy.
不过似乎你真生我气了
But you do seem awfully hissy.
再说能把你灌醉再成功得逞的机会
And there's an outside chance
可是千载难逢
that I could get you drunk and score.
只要你别认为这是我在认错
So as long as you don't take it as an admission of guilt,
那行  我去
sure, count me in.
一不小心真相了
A bit too much honesty?
周五晚的婚礼彩排你也得去
You're also going to the rehearsal dinner Friday night.
别穿太正式了
Dressy casual.
客房服务
Housekeeping.
要么是你疯了
Either you're crazy
要么是你在赎罪
or you're atoning for something naughty
而且还疯了
and you're crazy.
他是医生
He's a doctor.
我没在赎罪
I'm not atoning for anything.
看来你是疯了  多谢
That answers that. Thanks.
我女儿玛丽莎被确诊为脑癌晚期
My Marisa was diagnosed with terminal brain cancer.
第四阶段恶性胶质瘤
Stage iv glioblastoma.
当医生说她还能活两个月时
When the doctors said she had two months to live,
我决定要作笔交易
that's when I made my bargain.
跟你的医疗保险公司吗
With your health insurance carrier?
是跟上帝
With god.
-对哦  -我告诉他
- Oh. - I told him
我将每年把自己钉在十字架上
I would nail myself to a cross every year
只要他让她活下去
he kept her alive.
协商结果如何
How did that negotiation go?
难道上帝同意让你换成打耳洞了
You lowballed with ear piercing and god countered?
三周以后
Three weeks later,
她痊愈了
she was cancer-free.
这是四年前的事了
And that was four years ago.
彼拉多  多么伟大的肿瘤学家啊
Pontius Pilate-- misunderstood oncologist.
我前妻也以为我疯了
My ex-wife thinks I'm crazy too.
我第一次这么干时她就搬走了
She moved out the first time I did this.
至少你女儿还有个神智清醒的榜样在
Well, at least your daughter has one viable role model.
你不信仰上帝吗
You don't believe in god?
信啊  所以我长了卷发
I did. Then I grew my curly hairs.
那你以为我是怎么痊愈的
So how do you think I was cured?
或许一开始就是个误诊
Maybe you were misdiagnosed in the first place.
你们自有说法  医生
You have your answer, doctors.
但我们依然信仰上帝
We have ours.
宿命论认为
Causal determinism.
人生来就渴求得到答案
We are hardwired to need answers.
听到灌木丛里的沙沙声
The cave man who heard a rustle in the bushes
而外出查看的洞人
checked out to see what it was
比假设那只是阵风的洞人要活得久
lived longer than the guy who assumed it was just a breeze.
问题是  当我们无法找到合理的解释时
The problem is, when we don't find a logical answer,
就会找个蹩脚的糊弄自己
we settle for a stupid one.
宗教仪式就是我们丧失理智的产物
Ritual is what happens when we run out of rational.
要是你嘲讽完了  我们要准备做腰椎穿刺了
If you're done mocking him, we need to prep for an lp.
很好  多戳个洞  能让上帝更高兴
Good. Another hole in him should really make god's day.
你怎么迟到了
Why are you late?
要到明年一月你才见牙医
Your next dental appointment isn't till January,
八天前又刚见过你的全科医生
and you just saw your GP eight days ago.
你觉得一个患第四阶段恶性胶质瘤的八岁小孩
You think stage iv glioblastoma in an eight-year-old
能在三周内痊愈吗
could disappear in three weeks?
我轮胎没气了  你的病人得癌症了吗
I had a flat tire. Your patient has cancer?
你的轮胎还没跑够五千英里呢
Your tires got less than 5,000 miles on them.
我的病人没有  他女儿也没有
No, and neither does my patient's daughter.
在工地附近
I hit a piece of rebar
我压到了一条钢筋
near a construction site.
三周以内吗
In three weeks?
极度不可能
It's highly unlikely.
你家到这的路上可没什么工地
There's no construction site between here and your home.
我也觉得  我想是囊肿被误诊了
I agree. I think it was a misdiagnosed cyst.
但从干洗店到这里的路上有
But there is one between here and my dry cleaner.
可能是误诊
It could be a misdiagnosis,
也可能是自然痊愈
or it could be spontaneous remission.
但
But...
我有什么好骗你的
Why would I lie about this?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
但要在平时你早把领带一起干洗了
But you would have dropped off your tie.
上面有芥末渍
It's got a mustard stain.
我去买订婚戒指了
I was buying an engagement ring.
我打算在婚礼上向萨姆求婚
I'm gonna propose to Sam at the wedding.
这是我今天听到第二蠢的决定
That is the second stupidest thing I've heard today.
想不到你离第一蠢也不远了
And I'm surprised how close you came.
用不着买个新戒指
You don't need to buy her a new ring.
第一次的婚戒就足够用了
Isn't the first one good for all you can marry?
你大概还没跟卡迪道歉吧
I assume you haven't apologized to Cuddy yet.
看来你的愚蠢也需要时间让你清醒
Your stupidity demands equal time.
没什么好道歉的
Nothing to apologize for.
那就假装跟她道歉
Pretend to apologize.
你要我说谎吗
You want me to lie?
说谎有可爱的两面性
There's a lovely symmetry to it.
说谎能让你陷入麻烦
The lie got you into it.
也能让你摆脱麻烦
A lie gets you out of it.
每个人都说谎
Everybody lies.
我保证卡迪
I'm sure Cuddy...
只要给她这么个机会
Just need to give her a chance.
是啊  我还真就是这个意思
Yeah, that must have been what I meant.
有人见过准新娘了吗
Have you seen the bride-to-be?
美妞一个  年纪小他一半
Gorgeous woman half his age.
幸运男
He's a lucky guy.
暂且算是吧
Yeah, for a while.
我父亲比我母亲大19岁
My father's 19 years older than my mother,
他们幸福得共度了32年
and they've been happily married for 32 years.
我猜你爸爸不在福布斯财富榜上
I'm guessing your dad wasn't on the Forbes 400
你妈妈看着也不像泳装模特吧
and your mom didn't look like a swimsuit model.
抱歉  这话不太合适
Sorry. That didn't come out right.
我父亲是哥伦比亚大学的古典学教授
My father was the classics chair at Columbia,
我母亲是他的学生
and my mother was his student.
他的漂亮学生
His gorgeous student.
如果有人拿着手机
What's it mean when somebody takes
进浴室洗澡
their cell phone into the bathroom
说明什么
when they're taking a shower?
以防有人查他们的通话记录  电邮和短信
It means they don't want you to check their calls, emails, or texts.
如果我们说的是你老婆
If we're talking about your wife,
说明你是恶有恶报
it means the chickens are coming home to roost.
陶博出过轨
Taub has been known to dabble.
曾经
Used to be.
可能只是生活习惯
Maybe it's just a habit.
我就是这样的  我一个人住
I do that with my cell phone, and I live alone.
她今天1:30有个会议
She has a meeting today at 1:30.
地点在旅馆
At a hotel.
那我同意奇斯的说法
I'm gonna go with the chicken thing.
不是弓蛔虫  类杆菌
Negative for toxocara, Bacteroides,
蛔虫  什么都不是
Ascaris, everything.
那是什么看似感染
So what looks like an infection
而测试结果不是呢
but doesn't test like one?
动物
Animals.
我肯定你老婆见的是男人
I'm sure your wife's just seeing a dude.
病人在摩根建木工厂工作
Patient works for Morgan Timber Works.
名片上写着呢
Card's in the file.
负责搭建马厩  谷仓和摊位
Specializing in stables, barns, and stalls.
他工作中能接触到动物  是马红球菌
He works around animals. Rhodococcus equi.
要么这家伙真睡马槽里
Unless this guy's sleeping in the manger...
要么就是他曾有过开放伤
Or has a history of open wounds.
我们认为你感染了马红球菌
We think you have rhodococcus equi,
常感染马
a horse infection.
人类中很罕见
It's pretty rare in humans,
但用抗生素很容易治愈
but easily treatable with antibiotics.
会导致牙齿脱落吗
Does it make your teeth fall out?
不会
No.
那说明我们保不齐又搞错了
Then again, maybe we were wrong.
发热  咳血
Fever, coughing up blood,
咳牙
coughing up teeth.
要么就是他家上帝说了
So either God sweetened the deal
谁用牙线谁掉牙  要么
with a "No flossing" clause or...
辐射病
Radiation sickness.
是啊  没准那木匠造了个微波炉呢
Yeah, maybe the carpenter builds microwave ovens.
卡波氏肉瘤
Kaposi's sarcoma?
未见皮肤损伤
No skin lesions.
符合重金属中毒症状
Heavy metal poisoning fits.
罐头金枪鱼  寿司  白铅漆
Canned tuna, sushi, lead paint.
就它了  去他家搜查一下
Heavy metal it is. Do a home search
周边探查一下
and a peripheral smear.
去不了  我有点私事要去办
I can't. I have a personal errand to run.
想去抓你老婆的奸夫吗
Trying to catch your wife cheating?
你何出此言
Oh... Why would you say that?
光环暗淡
Missing mojo.
气势低落
Posture's slumped.
情绪萎靡
Expression defeated.
懒得据理力争
Didn't try to back up your theory.
而且奇斯告密
And Chase told me.
去吧  把光环找回来
Go. Find your mojo.
售货小姐  我需要一份病历
Shopkeeper? I need a patient file.
去档案科找
Ask records.
不是我们的病人
Not one of our patients.
是我病人的女儿
My patient's daughter.
找你病人要
Ask your patient.
他觉得我的目的是拆穿他的信仰
He thinks I only want it to debunk his faith.
他为什么这么想
And why would he think that?
因为这蠢蛋眼力倒挺好
Because he's strangely perceptive for an idiot.
莫非我要为了让你高兴
And I'm going to violate patient privacy laws
而违反医患保密条例吗
just to keep you happy?
我好  你也好嘛
You keep me happy, I return the favor.
我必将涌泉相报
Think of it as tat for tit.
工作场所
When we're at work,
只谈工作  不谈其他
we need to focus on our work thoughts.
你干嘛穿成这样
Why are you wearing that?
我休闲装就这样
It's my dressy casual.
觉得怎样
What do you think?
看起来像威尔森
You look like Wilson.
很诡异
It looks weird.
你明知道我的看法
Well, you knew I'd think that.
倒是你失望的神情让我很是好奇
which makes me wonder why you look disappointed.
你伤害了我  我还一笑而过么
If you prick me, do I not bleed?
你明知我不会喜欢  可你觉得我会谎称喜欢
You knew I wouldn't like it, but you thought i would say I did.
原来你在琢磨这个
That's what this is about.
你想骗我撒谎
You're trying to trap me into lying to you.
是吗  听起来好幼稚
You sure? 'cause that sounds so juvenile.
不排斥擅闯民宅了吗
You're okay with burglary now?
我请求过许可了
I asked his permission.
我们以前不请求许可
The reason we don't ask permission
是因为害怕病人有所隐瞒
is we're afraid the patient is going
可这位病人不住家  独居
to hide something, but our patient hasn't been home, lives alone.
无依无靠
He doesn't have any help,
没有隐藏的动机
and he has no motive to hide anything.
你问他拿钥匙没有
Did you ask for his key too?
他没有
Oh, doesn't have one.
明白原因了
And now we know why.
你觉得他是疯子吗
You think he's crazy?
不是疯子能自己上十字架嘛
Crucifixion's pretty convincing evidence.
有白铅漆吗
Lead paint?
这房子太新了
The place is too new.
他相信超自然力量会影响他的生活
He believes in a higher power that can affect his life.
这点上与其他人无异
Like most people on the planet.
没错  但另一方面  却自虐至此
True. On the other hand, crucified himself.
没有罐头金枪鱼
No canned tuna.
看起来寿司也不大可能
And I don't think we have to worry about sushi.
没电脑  没电视
No computer. No television.
没音乐  他平时都干嘛
No music. What does he do?
看书
He reads.
已经证明  祈祷有助于恢复
Prayer's been proven to aid recovery.
只有当他知道有人为他祈祷才管用
Only if the person knows they're being prayed for.
也就是说客观上无用
Means there's no objective effect.
信仰本由心生
So faith comes from within.
也不是什么稀奇事
Not exactly a newsflash.
看来忧国忧民确实催人消瘦
I guess worry is good for the waistline.
不是忧虑所致
It's not worry.
是饥饿
It's starvation.
他的牙齿脱落
His tooth didn't fall out
不是因为重金属中毒
because of heavy metal poisoning.
是由于营养不良
It fell out because of malnutrition.
他确实感染了马红球菌
He does have rhodococcus equi.
陶博是对的
Taub was right.
只是原因不明而已
He just didn't know why.
锁上了
It's locked.
我很忙
I'm busy!
我等着
I'll wait.
我真的很忙
I really am busy.
卡迪给我找来了女儿的病历
Cuddy got me the daughter's file.
倒不是她本人  签名而已
Well, not Cuddy exactly. Her signature.
倒也不是她本人签名
Well, not exactly her signature.
你又扯谎
Another lie?
想来找你帮忙看看
Thought you could take a look at it for me.
你没听清吗  我很忙
Maybe you hadn't heard. I'm kind of busy.
忙啥
With what?
数独  你以为呢
Sudoku. What do you think?
我作为一家大医院的肿瘤科主管
I'm the head of oncology at a major hospital.
可是  这些病历并非来自本院
And yet these files are not from this hospital.
这是从准老婆纪念医院弄来的
These are from where-my-fiancee-works memorial.
萨姆的老板要用她的所有病历
Sam's boss is doing a clinical review
做一个临床综述
of all of her files,
她只是想在他周一开工前
And she just wanted to make sure
把东西整理出一个头绪来
everything was in order before he starts on monday.
难怪她忙得没时间帮我看病历
Which explains why Sam is too busy to look at my file.
我要是不帮她  她就去不了婚礼
If I don't help her, she can't go to the wedding and...
我们在她表亲的婚礼上相爱
We fell in love at her cousin's wedding,
所以我想在婚礼上向她求婚
which is why I want to propose to her at a wedding.
我现在给你一分钟时间
And now you have 60 seconds
对我这一行为以及帮老婆做作业这事儿
to berate me for that and for helping my girlfriend
尽情吐槽
with her homework.
可千万别在婚礼上求婚
You don't want to propose at a wedding.
大家都情绪高涨  人都疯了似的
Emotions running high, people on edge.
你应该去个佛家寺庙之类的地方
You ought to try somewhere like a buddhist temple
水族馆也行
or an aquarium.
或者佛家水族馆
Or a buddhist aquarium.
十秒搞定
That only took ten seconds.
省下的时间你可以帮我看病历了
You can spend the rest of the time on my file.
瑞秋
Rachel?
还有多久到家
Hey. How long before you're home?
快了
Not long.
你电脑忘关了
Uh, you left your laptop on.
我今天看到你了
Saw you today.
在宾馆那边
At the hotel.
你是去查岗吗
Were you checking up on me?
对
Yes.
满意没
Satisfied?
满意了
Yes.
很好
Good.
就这样
That's it?
你都说了满意了
You said you're satisfied.
不就行了嘛
It's enough.
你不好奇我为什么这样吗
You're not wondering why it started.
貌似你不想让我谈起这事
That makes me think you don't want to talk about this,
这不禁让我觉得
which makes me think...
你太多疑了
You're being paranoid.
你今天早上洗澡的时候
You took your cell phone with you into the bathroom
把手机带进了浴室
when you took your shower this morning.
我交了个新朋友
I made a new friend.
网上的
Online.
在一个互助小组里
In a support group.
男人吗
A guy?
是的
Yes.
什么样的互助小组
A support group for what?
配偶出轨的互助小组
For people with unfaithful spouses.
为什么不告诉我们你在刻意节食
Why didn't you tell us you were starving yourself?
我不是故意的
Well, I wasn't trying to.
我现在手头很紧  而且这食量也过得去
I'm on a tight budget, and it seemed like an okay diet.
不管怎样  你看上去好多了
Well, you seem to be felling better.
不觉得  我的腿疼死了
Not really. My legs are killing me.
有多疼
How bad is the pain?
从一到十  十表示最疼
On a scale of one to ten, ten being the worst.
九点五吧
9 1/2.
那你为什么还笑
Then why are you smiling?
我没笑
I'm not smiling.
腿疼加上假延髓病症状
Leg pain and pseudobulbar affect.
他感受的是一种情绪
He's feeling one emotion
但却无意识地表达出另一种
while unknowingly expressing another one.
典型的神经紊乱
Classic neurohecatia.
吃两天抗胆碱能药物
Two days of anticholinergics,
你就能痊愈出院了
You'll be walking out of here.
真的吗
Really?
不  我就是编出来看看你的反应的
No. I just made that up to see your reaction.
诊断测试
Diagnostic test.
简直太帅了
This is awesome.
一名三十三岁的木匠表现出恋己癖
33-year-old carpenter presenting with narcissism,
夸大妄想症  并出现幻觉
delusions of grandeur, hallucinations.
他没有产生幻觉
He hasn't had hallucinations.
我说的不是他
I'm not talking about him.
说的是"他"
I'm talking about "Him"
原主保佑的那位主
with a capital "O-M-G."
你想让我们对耶稣基督做鉴别诊断吗
You want us to do a differential diagnosis on Jesus?
他出现幻听  自以为是上帝之子
Hears voices, thinks he's the son of god.
很可能是精神分裂
Probably schizophrenic.
我觉得你触怒他了
I think you offended him.
你是说病人的宗教极端主义
You're saying the patient's religious extremism
也可能是症状之一
could be a symptom.
神经紊乱症可以解释所有的妄想症状
A neuro disorder could explain all his delusions.
给他做个脑部核磁共振
Get an MRI of his brain.
看看咱们能不能找到上帝
Let's see if we can find god.
听说你拿到了那女儿的病历
Heard you got the daughter's file.
病人改主意了吗
Patient change his mind?
我伪造了你的签名
I forged your signature.
多谢你的直言不讳
Thank you for your honesty.
权当我送你的礼物好了
Think of it as a present.
再几个月某人就要四十五了
See, somebody is about to turn the big 4-5 in several months,
而另有其人  想大肆庆祝一番
and somebody else wants to make a very big deal of it.
是四十三
4-3.
四十三
-你确定吗  -相当确定
- Are you sure? - Very.
我怎么会犯这种错误
How could I make such a mistake?
我可看过你的人事档案啊
In reading your H.R. file?
不  等等  我没看错
Oh, no, wait, I didn't.
于是  平地一声惊雷
And boom goes the dynamite.
说谎比分持平  咱们两不相欠了
Scores are tied. We are even steven.
你说得不错
You're right.
我确实撒谎了  骗的是人事处不是你
I did lie. To H.R. not to you.
我最初申请副院长职务的时候
When I first applied for the VP admin job,
才二十九岁
I was 29 years old.
我想要是自己刚好三十出头
I knew I would be taken more seriously
别人肯定会更把我当回事儿
if I were in my first 30s,
所以我虚报了两岁
so I added two years to my age.
你为了让自己变老而撒谎吗
You lied to make yourself older?
莫非你还是个伪娘
Are you lying about being a woman?
就算我中了你的套
Even if you can trap me,
你觉得我会突然对说谎大加赞赏吗
you think I'll suddenly embrace the value of lying?
我想说的是你早就撒过谎
My point is you already have.
我只是需要证明这点
I just need to prove it.
不是恶有恶报
Chickens aren't roosting.
她只是交了个朋友
She's just got a friend.
在网上配偶出轨互助小组认识了一个男的
A guy she met in an online support group for cheating spouses.
我听说过那个小组
I've heard of that group.
名叫世事讽刺
It's called irony.
你觉得她正背着你
You think she's cheating on her spouse
和那个在互助小组认识的人交往吗
with someone from a cheating spouse support group?
听来像是钓到脆弱女人的好地方
Sounds like the perfect place to hit on vulnerable women.
看  多重高密度损伤
Look. Multiple dense lesions.
看上去像是多发性硬化
It looks like M.S.
我们怎会漏掉多发性硬化呢
How did we miss M.S.?
被之前营养不良掩盖了症状
It was hiding behind the malnutrition.
多发性硬化攻击免疫系统
M.S. attacks the immune system.
免疫缺陷  就没有症状
No system, no symptoms.
而我们现在给他吃的  使两种症状并现了
And now we're feeding him, so they're both back.
你感觉怎样
How are you feeling?
糟透了
Terrible.
看得出来
Obviously.
你的朋友们呢
Where are your friends?
还在"为你的里衣拈阄"吗
Still casting lots for your clothes?
我只求他们为我祈祷
All I ask is that they pray for me.
总是舍己为人
Always sacrificing.
真是鼓舞人心
Very inspirational.
你的颞叶区出现病变
The lesions are in your temporal lobes.
当这些区域变得紊乱时
When those areas get messed with,
人们就会感受到一些离奇的经历
people have strange experiences--
比如鬼怪附身  被外星人绑架  穿越
like hauntings, alien abductions, past lives.
和上帝做交易也算吗
Deals with god?
你不是来看我病情有没有好转的
You didn't come to see if I was better.
而是来看药物是否能把我变成个无神论者
You came to see if your medicine has turned me into an atheist.
变成不可知论者我也认了
I'd settle for agnostic.
有信仰不是一种病
Faith is not a disease.
不 当然不是
No, of course not.
但从另一方面来说  它会传染
On the other hand, it is communicable,
而且害死过很多人
and it kills a lot of people.
我胳膊不能动了
I can't move my arm.
有感觉吗
You feel that?
看来你的朋友们祈祷得还不够
Your friends are not praying hard enough.
不是多发性硬化
It's not M.S.
麻痹是多发性硬化的症状之一
Paralysis is a symptom of M.S.A
腿疼和假性延髓病感染也是
So are leg pain and pseudobulbar affect.
他用了强的松后病情恶化了
He's getting worse on the prednisone.
不是多发性硬化
It's not M.S.
核磁共振结果也一目了然
The MRI was clear.
他脑组织有病变
He has lesions.
可能是血管畸形  脑梗塞
Could be an AVM, cerebral infarction.
举手表决吧
Let's put it to the vote.
背心还是腰带
Vest or cummerbund?
腰带
Cummerbund.
你真了解我
You know me.
我反驳不了你们中的任何一位
I can't say no to any of you guys.
你们说的都对
You're all correct.
他是得了多发性硬化
He has M.S.
但不是友好的邻家大叔型
But not the friendly Mr. Rogers M.S.
而是开集装箱的怪叔叔类型
This is the weird guy in the panel van kind.
马尔堡式多发性硬化吗
Marburg M.S.?
我刚说什么来着
What did I just say?
那他顶多只能活两三天了
He'll be dead in two to three days at the most.
除非我们能赶紧找个人
That's unless we can get someone
把自己钉在十字架上
to nail themselves to a cross as soon as possible.
或者用干细胞疗法
Or stem cell treatment.
这还是一种实验性疗法
That's an experimental treatment.
对脱髓鞘类疾病有显著疗效
That's had promising results with demyelinating diseases.
这是我们最好的选择
It's our best shot.
这得用胚胎干细胞治疗才有效果
It would be if it wasn't embryonic stem cell treatment.
咱们的病人一心朝圣
Our patient's right of the pope.
他是不会同意的
He's never gonna consent to that.
这事你知  我知
I know that, and you know that.
他并不知
He doesn't know that.
但现在被她知道了
But now she knows that,
他也早晚会知道
he's gonna know that.
有本事
Way to go.
确认是不是马尔堡病
Confirm Marburg.
再看看他是不是伪君子
Then see if he's a fair-weather flagellator.
玛尼佩妮小姐  你看起来容光焕发
You look smashing, Miss Moneypenny.
系宽腰带
Cummerbund?
样子很蠢  邦德先生
Very foolish, Mr. Bond.
他女儿的病是真的
The daughter's case checks out.
立体定向活检已经确认
Stereotactic biopsy confirmed
是四期多形性胶质母细胞瘤
stage IV glioblastoma multiforme.
化疗对其无效
Doesn't respond to chemo,
但医生们死马当活马医  结果发生了奇迹
But they gave it to her anyway as a Hail Mary and just got lucky.
要么真是上帝帮了忙  一种省事的解释
So either God intervened, which is a lazy explanation,
要么我们不知道为什么
Or we just don't know why.
这是没有解释
Which is no explanation.
有些事情就是解释不通
Sometimes there is no explanation.
我也不是很在意
And I'm just fine with that.
这让我十分受不了
Which annoys me to no end.
把那份文件还给我  还有椅子和桌子
I need that file, that chair, and that desk.
你女朋友篡改了事实
Your woman is fudging the facts.
五个病人
Five of those cases,
他们受到的放射性损伤与她说的剂量并不符合
the stated doses don't explain the radiation damage.
不同病人敏感度不一
Sensitivities vary.
差别不会那么大
Not that much.
是呀  我也是这样想的
Yeah. That's what I thought.
我直接了当问过她
I asked her point blank about this.
她说辐射剂量是准确的
She said the dosages were accurate,
她没犯任何错误
and that she had done nothing wrong.
从道德角度讲  她确实没做错
Because morally she didn't.
五个病人都已经到了晚期
All five patients were terminal.
她使用了高于标准的剂量
She exceeded the dosing protocols
试图挽救他们的生命
to try to save their life.
换作你也会做同样的事情
You would have done the same.
她是个傻冒  跟你绝配
She's a sap, and she's perfect for you.
我讨厌婚礼  也同样讨厌彩排宴会
I hate rehearsal dinners almost as much as I hate weddings.
一般人结婚的唯一原因
The only reason anyone gets married
是雌性直立人在哺乳时需要保护
is that homo erectus females needed protection
免受野兽攻击
from predators while breast feeding.
他们两个结婚的唯一原因
The only reason these two are getting married
就是为了举办一场恶心的晚会
is to throw an obnoxious gala
让参加宴会的人感到自惭形秽
and make the rest of us feel unworthy.
虽然我们可以断定不出两年时间
Even though we know in two years
他们的律师就会开始相互争夺财产
their lawyers are gonna be fighting over the Bentleys.
多么美妙的祝酒辞
That'll make a lovely toast.
男财女貌
She's got looks. He's got money.
没一个是永恒的
One of them is bound to run out.
我估计19个月
I give it 19 months.
怎么这么具体
That's very specific.
新泽西州法律规定
No fault divorce in New Jersey
夫妻双方均无过错
requires couples to live
分居满18个月才可以离婚
at least 18 months apart.
真算起来我只给他们几个礼拜
I'm actually only giving it a few weeks.
我以为我才是悲观者
Oh. Thought I was supposed to be the dark one.
今天不是
Not today.
说
Yeah.
你得一个人赴宴了
You're gonna have to go stag.
我的病人拒绝接受治疗
My patient is refusing treatment.
-你在乎呀  -不
- And you care? - No.
但这个借口你必须接受
But it's an excuse you can't argue with.
接受治疗就是对上帝不敬
Accepting this treatment is an insult to God.
就不能指望他遵守约定了
I can't expect Him to keep our deal.
你已经违反了约定
You already broke it.
根据你的验血报告
Your blood test showed
你体内含有大量布洛芬
you were loaded with ibuprofen.
吃止疼药也算违反约定吗
Taking painkillers breaks my deal?
你就想像你救世主那样受难  对吧
The point is to suffer like your Savior did, right?
他又没吃"没药"  古罗马时期的扑热息痛
Well, He didn't take Myrrh, the Tylenol of ancient Rome.
再说他钉子钉在手腕上
And His nails went through His wrists,
不是手掌
not through His palms.
懦夫才会钉在手掌上
Palms are for sissies.
还有那三十九下的鞭笞
And what about the 39 lashes
拳打脚踢和荆棘冠呢
And the beatings and the crown of thorns?
你经受的痛苦顶多是剪坏了手指甲
What you go through is closer to a bad manicure
跟耶稣受难差远了
than a crucifixion.
这不是为了向上帝表明我受了苦
It's not about showing God my pain.
而是为了表明我对他的信仰
It's about showing Him my faith.
如果他让我为我女儿去死
If He asks me to die for my daughter,
我会欣然接受
I'll do it gladly.
别拿你女儿说事儿
Don't make this about your daughter.
你只是害怕如果我们找到治疗方法
You're just worried that if we find a cure,
你就会失去信仰
that it'll cost you your faith.
变得跟普通人一样了
And then you'll be like the rest of us.
孤独又害怕
Alone and afraid?
你说得对
You're right.
-我不想那样  -你笑了
- I don't want that. - You're smiling.
是不是表示你对自己的选择
Does that mean that you're comfortable
很满意
with your choice?
还是你在害怕
Or that you're afraid?
因为这可能是你唯一的希望
Because this may be your only hope.
你可以开出各种处方
You can prescribe a lot of things,
但开不出"希望"
but hope isn't one of 'em.
坚持自己的信念
Sticking by your convictions
不计一切的后果
and damning the consequences.
你们两个挺相像
You two have a lot in common.
都是傻瓜
You're both idiots.
所有的信念都同样荒谬吗
All conviction's equally ridiculous?
不看情形死板的坚持就是
Just when they're applied indiscriminately to all circumstances.
他需要见见他女儿
He needs to see his daughter.
他需要看"向上帝挑战"
He needs to see Inherit the Wind.
告诉她女儿他要死了
And tell her he's dying
因为上帝不想让他吃药
because God doesn't want him to take his medicine.
诚实也不是一无是处
Honesty's not all bad.
把她找来
Get her in here.
吃了那些药  你还可以继续活下去
You don't have to die, not if you take their medicine.
这治疗违背上帝的原则
The treatment violates god's laws.
他不希望我接受
He doesn't want me to take it.
可上帝也不希望你死去
But God doesn't want you to die.
他不希望任何人死去  神的国度里只有爱
He doesn't want anyone to die. He's all about love.
我知道这是你妈妈教你的
I know this is coming from your mother.
这是我自己的想法
This is coming from me.
我去鬼门关闯过一次
I'm the one who almost died.
我知道什么感觉
I know what it's like.
你是我爸爸  你不能死
And you're my dad. You can't die.
我也希望我可以活下去
I wish I didn't have to.
爸爸  你可以活下去
You don't have to, daddy.
只要把药吃了
Just take the medicine.
你总是让我好好吃药  求你了
You always tell me to take the medicine. Please.
总有一天
One day,
你会理解的
you're going to understand.
我不理解
No, I'm not.
我永远也不能理解
I am never going to understand that.
如果上帝真这样做
If God could do this,
我会痛恨他
I hate God.
我刚在巧克力喷泉那儿
I just spotted a couple of hot girls
瞄到几个辣妹
by the chocolate fountain.
你刚才不是在楼上跟...
Weren't you just upstairs with...
要不是兄弟你  我哪能有这福气呀
And it wouldn't have happened if not for you, buddy.
总得有人把没喝醉的朋友支开吧
Someone had to distract the sober friend.
我可不是来给你当跟班的
I'm not here to be your wingman.
这次我给你当跟班
I'll be your wingman this time.
我也不是来找女人的
I didn't come here to get lady.
那就不找
Then don't.
跟美女搭讪一点都没意思
Talking to beautiful women isn't nearly as much fun
还不如看陶博如何不搭理他老婆呢
as watching Taub not talking to his wife.
我看了你的电子邮件
I went through your emails.
里面没有任何不合适的内容
There's nothing in there that's inappropriate.
我们只是朋友
We're friends, Chris.
可是你给他讲的事  从不对我说
But you tell him things that you've never told me.
我没法告诉你  所以才对他讲
I tell him things I can't tell you. That's the point.
你说的全是你的事  从来不提我
Not things about me. About you.
你换了新工作  染了头发
About your new job. About coloring your hair.
你母亲去世时你的感受
About how you felt when your mother died.
这些事情我都想知道
I want to know those things.
跟他交流很容易
He's easy to talk to.
他心态开放  诚实
He's open and honest.
让我有安全感
He makes me feel safe.
听上去像是你爱上他了
Sounds like you love him.
我没有出轨
I am not having an affair.
他住在俄勒冈州  我从没见过他
He lives in Oregon. I've never met him.
很可能永远也不会见到他
I probably never will.
你出轨了  感情上
You are having an affair. An emotional one.
你把我现在的事和你以前所为划等号吗
Are you equating what I'm doing with what you did?
我做过非常对不起你的事情
I've done terrible things to you,
会有今天是我罪有应得
And I deserve all of this and more,
可你不能装作你现在的行为不伤害我的感情
but you can't pretend that what you're doing isn't hurtful.
某人今晚很迷人嘛
Someone looks lovely tonight.
谢谢
Thank you.
我说我自己
I meant me.
另一位某人美得惊艳
Someone else looks simply stunning.
这次是说你  还有吧台那金发美女
That was you. And the blonde at the bar.
澄清一点
Just to be clear,
你这次小小表现没用的
this whole little act isn't gonna work.
我需要的是道歉
I need an apology.
不是奉承
Not flattery.
这不是表现
It's not an act.
是婚礼嘛
It's the wedding.
-你讨厌婚礼  -我以为我讨厌
- You hate weddings.  - I thought I did.
然后我意识到  我从没参加过婚礼
Then I realized I've never been to one.
从没有
Never?
原来婚礼还是蛮好玩的
Turns out they're kind of fun.
我可不能说上司坏话
Well, I can't complain about my boss.
他人就在这儿呢
He's right here.
你是他上司
You're his boss?
仅限周一至周五
Only Mondays through Fridays.
周末的时候  他是我好兄弟
On the weekends, he's my bra.
这一轮好兄弟请了
This round's on the bra.
你女儿的事  对不起
I'm sorry about your daughter.
我无意伤害她
I never meant to hurt her.
你以为她能令我改变主意
You just thought she would change my mind.
我很惊讶她没能说服你
I was surprised she didn't.
我也很惊讶
So was I.
我说我不怕死
I didn't tell you the truth,
那不是真话
when I said I'm not afraid to die.
不过你死后会上天堂  所以
But you're going straight to heaven, so...
我相信是那样  可我也是人
That's what I believe, but I'm human.
所以你知道  自己可能是错的
So you know you may be wrong.
你是怎么做到的
How could you do what you just did?
所以人才需要有信仰
That's why we have beliefs.
当我们被怀疑和恐惧蒙蔽了双眼
So we can still see the right thing to do
只有信仰能让我们看到正确的路
when we're blinded with doubt and fear.
信仰告诉我们自己是谁
Our beliefs define us.
丢掉了信仰
If we lose them,
我们又成了什么呢
who are we?
听我说  对不起
Look, I'm sorry.
刚才闹成那样不是我的本意
I didn't mean for it to go that way.
你认为我这样是为我自己
You think I'm being selfish,
但我不是
but I'm not.
他让我对自己和我们的关系都看开了许多
He makes me feel better about me and about us.
这说法不太容易接受
Well, that is hard to believe,
因为我现在只觉得被背叛了
because all I feel right now is betrayed.
我没想要你这样
I never wanted that.
很好
Good.
因为正如你当初要求我停止我的行为
Because just like you asked me to stop my behavior,
我也要求你停止这种行为
I'm asking you to stop this.
不行吗
No?
我不会骗你
I'm not gonna lie to you.
你是在报复我吗
Is this revenge?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只知道这是我现在需要的
But I do know that it's something I need right now.
你婚礼上会穿什么
What would you wear?
我钟情白色婚纱
Well, I'm a sucker for the white gown.
第一次结婚的年轻新娘的传统选择
Traditionally for young, first-time brides.
我或许是不年轻
Well, I may not be young,
但会是我第一次结婚
but I'll be first-time.
你骗人
That is a lie.
你之前结过婚
You were married before.
1987年  为时六天
1987 for six days.
你对新泽西州离婚法的熟悉令我生疑
Your knowledge of new Jersey divorce law made me suspicious,
所以我做了调查
so I looked it up.
这些都是你的陷阱
So this was all your trap?
陷阱太原始
Trap's primitive.
我更喜欢骗局
I prefer inveiglement.
总之重点是  我骗了你  你也骗了我
Anyway, the point is, I lied to you, you lied to me,
我原谅你
I forgive you.
演得好
Well played.
你是不是累了  看了那么多文件
You're tired, aren't you? All those files?
不累
No.
我是在想
No, I was thinking...
如果他俩能有百万分之一的机会白头到老
I mean, if those two even have the slightest chance of making it,
那我们一定能
then we have to be a sure thing.
而且我们该犯的错误都已经犯过了
And we've already made all our mistakes.
而且
And...
我意识到
I've come to realize
我比想象中更爱你
that I love you even more than I thought I did.
萨姆  你愿意再嫁我一次吗
Sam, will you marry me again?
我不知说什么才好
Wow. I don't even know what to say.
我有备选答案哦
I have a suggestion.
你怎么会突然求婚
Where did this even come from?
你是什么时候
When did you...
你说你刚刚意识到什么事让你更爱我了
You just came to realize what made you love me even more?
你做的每一件事
Everything you've done.
你的工作   你的
Your work. Your...
你的道德感
Your sense of morality.
那五个病例
The five cases.
对你的做法我不仅赞同
I not only agree with what you did.
而且钦佩
I admire it.
我什么都没有做
I didn't do anything.
你之前已经问过我了
You already asked me about the files.
-我也对你说了实话  -我知道
- And I told you the truth.  - I know.
我能明白
And I get it.
你不相信我
You don't believe me.
我相信你是个非常好的人
I believe that you are a wonderful person.
一个撒谎的骗子
Who lies and cheats.
不  萨姆  听我说  我是支持你的
No, Sam, listen. I'm on your side.
我不敢相信
I can't believe this.
萨姆  萨姆  别走
Sam. Sam, don't do this...
一共几个妞
So how many do you think?
至少三个
At least three.
奇斯上演帽子戏法
A hat trick, Chase.
看到啦  单身汉的生活
See? The life of the bachelor.
充满激情  毫无愧疚
All of the sex, none of the guilt.
这事没完
It's not over, okay?
我只是判断错误
I just really miscalculated.
我以为她已经原谅了我
I thought she'd forgiven me for everything.
可是那些被我伤害的感情
All those hurt feelings,
从没真正消失
they never really went away.
这样说有道理得多
That makes a lot more sense.
不用理他
Ignore him.
他又来灵感了
He just got an idea.
我还有项测验要做
I have one more test to run.
我恨婚礼
Ugh. I hate weddings.
末日近了
It won't be long now.
在你还没反应过来之前  就要面临永恒的虚无
You'll be staring down the yawning void before you know it.
你从婚礼上跑回来就为了告诉我这些
You came from a wedding to tell me that?
不  我跑回来
Nope. I came from a wedding
为了做个PET扫描
to run a PET-scan.
我以为你已经放弃我了
I thought you'd given up on me.
我是放弃了
I have.
PET扫描是为你女儿安排的
PET-scan was for your daughter.
她的诊断我弄错了
I was wrong about her.
她的确得了恶性胶质母细胞瘤
She did have Glioblastoma.
而且现在还有
And she still does.
肿瘤从未去除
The cancer never went away.
不  已经没有了
Yes, it did.
医生每年都给她检查
They tested her every year.
做的是CT
With a CT-scan.
会漏掉各种微小肿瘤
Which misses all the tiny, little tumors
但PET不会
that a PET-scan doesn't.
你弄错了
You've made a mistake.
她已经没有癌症了
She does not have cancer anymore.
我查过两遍了
I ran it twice.
没弄错
No mistake.
似乎上帝违约了
Looks like god broke your deal.
对不起
I'm sorry.
但我说的是事实
But I'm also right.
你就是个混蛋
You're a bastard.
想怎样治随你吧
Do whatever you want to me.
明智的决定
Good call.
真令人吃惊  你还有精力来上班
Surprised you've got enough strength to come to work today.
一天半的时间够我恢复了
36 hours is long enough for me to recover.
可要让这家伙好起来还差远了
And not nearly long enough for this guy to be getting better.
豪斯交待无论如何要每12小时检查一次
House wanted us checking every 12 hours anyway.
抱歉我丢下你了
Sorry I took off on you.
两次哦
Twice?
第一次是我不应该
First one was my bad.
第二次我没得选啊
Second one, I had no choice.
那可是3P哎
It was a threesome.
3P也没多大了不起
They're overrated.
他在吹牛
He's bluffing.
叫豪斯来
Get house.
给你看点东西
Got something to show you.
这是你女儿的PET扫描结果
Your daughter's PET-scan.
没东西
It's clean.
健健康康
She's fine.
我的错
My bad.
我把她和马里恩·西尔弗搞混了
Got her mixed up with Marion Silver.
玛丽莎·席尔瓦
Marisa Silva.
这个可以有  对吧
That's believable, right?
总之  对你来说是个好消息
Anyhow, good news for you,
对席尔瓦先生来说可就是个坏消息了
Bad news for Mr. Silver.
你耍我
You tricked me.
上帝从来就没有违约
God didn't break our deal.
是我
I did.
你抛给我诱惑
You led me into temptation.
我陷进去了
And I followed.
上帝会因此而惩罚你的
And God will punish you for that.
-必须的  -因为如果他不
-He has to. -'cause if he didn't,
你肯定百思不得其解了  对吧
Well, that would make you wonder, wouldn't it?
他会的
He will.
所以我就想不通了
Well, that's why I'm so confused by this.
这是你的核磁共振
This is your MRI.
显示病情明显改善
Shows incremental improvement.
你正在好转
You're getting better.
我这次反复核对了姓名
I double-checked the name on this one.
不过也不完全是好消息
But it's not all good news.
这个病人完蛋了
This patient is screwed.
说正经点叫做必死无疑
Technical term is dead as a doornail.
这是谁
Who is that?
上帝
God.
你违了约
You broke your deal with him,
你女儿没事  你正在好转
your daughter's fine, you're getting better.
没有不幸的事发生
Nothing bad happened.
这只能说明一件事情
Which can only mean one thing.
根本就没有上帝
There is no God.
当然  要是你女儿今天被流星砸到
Of course, if your daughter gets hit by a meteorite today,
我就要遭受愤怒的鸡蛋了
I would have some serious egg on my face.
你在笑
You're smiling.
我猜这是你痛苦的表现吧
I assume that means you're miserable.
我很高兴
It means I'm happy.
这证明不了上帝不存在
It doesn't mean God doesn't exist.
只能说明上帝他  真的很仁慈
It just means he's-- he's truly merciful.
我美丽的玛丽莎说得对
My beautiful Marisa was right.
神的国度里只有爱
God is all about love.
有惩罚证明上帝存在
Punishment is proof of God,
没有惩罚也证明上帝存在
and no punishment is proof of god?
这论点很有创意
Ingenious argument.
信仰不需要论证
Faith isn't an argument.
我要见我女儿
I'd like to see my daughter.
其他人都知道你的计划吗
Everyone else knew?
我信得过的人都知道
Everyone I could trust.
所以是滴
So yes.
如果你预先告诉我  他现在已经死了
If you had told me, he'd be dead by now.
那为什么我还要说实话
So why do I still want to tell the truth?
要么你是天真要么就是有良心
Either you're naive or you have scruples.
我不知道哪个更坏事
I'm not sure which is worse.
这太出格了  我们不能这么干
This is insane. We can't work like this.
我能
I can.
萨姆
Sam?
抱歉  我本想在你回来前收拾好
Sorry. I was hoping to be done before you got home.
我们是吵了一架
We had a fight.
就吵了这么一架
We had one fight.
我也已经认过错了
And I admitted I was wrong.
我们可以坐下来谈啊  把这一切都忘掉
We can talk about it. We can get over it.
这关乎信任
This is about trust.
我从没对你撒过任何谎
I never lied to you about anything.
我知道  我也一直信任你
I know. And I always trusted you.
我...
I...
不然我们去看婚姻咨询师
Maybe we could talk to a counselor.
你说过上次离婚后  那很管用
You said that helped after our divorce.
是有用  我觉得我改变了很多
It did. And I think I changed a lot.
难道我没改变吗
And I haven't?
这是我的错吗
This is my fault?
我知道会有什么结果
I know where this is going.
我不想重蹈覆辙
And I don't want to go there again.
你在退缩  萨姆
You're quitting, Sam.
你又退缩了
You're quitting again.
所以看来你并没有改变多少
So I guess you haven't changed that much.
今天干得不错
Good work today.
我都不担心你的病人会告你
I don't even think your patient's gonna sue.
总算皆大欢喜了
It looks like everybody's happy.
我一直太愚了
I've been an idiot.
固执己见以为很有道理
I got this argument stuck in my head.
如果人人都撒谎
If everybody lies,
信任就既无根据也没意义
then trust is not only unfounded and pointless,
成了虚假
it's fictional.
但信任绝不是一场辩论
But trust is not an argument
它争不出个输赢
that can be won or lost.
或许我该放下我的愤世嫉俗  开始有点信仰
Maybe I just have to suspend my cynicism and believe.
或许我该迈出这一步了
Maybe it's time I took a leap of faith.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不会再对你撒谎了
I won't lie to you again.
谢谢你
Thank you.
萨姆离开我了
Sam left me.
真是白痴
What a moron.
太快了吧  我还爱着她呢
Too soon. I'm still in love with her.
我是说你
I meant you.
有酒吗  越多越好
Do you have a drink? Or drinks?
卡迪要过来
Cuddy's coming over.
她知道你在这儿吗
Does she know you're here?
我跟她道歉了
I apologized to her.
很好啊
Good for you.
不见得
Not really.
我撒谎了
I lied.
我只是采纳了你的建议
I just took your advice.
可惜你自己却没有
Too bad you didn't.
真有你的
Good for you.